newtek.com 2016-11-19

# Privacy Policy

**NewTek, Inc. Privacy Policy**

**PLEASE READ CAREFULLY, THIS GOVERNS THE USE OF INFORMATION WE OBTAIN.**

This policy covers information collected by NewTek, Inc. (NewTek) on its website [www.newtek.com](http://www.newtek.com/) and on NewTek’s online store (Store or Online Store) at [store.newtek.com](http://store.newtek.com/) (collectively referred to as NewTek Website or Website). This Privacy Policy is part of the Terms of Use of NewTek Websites, and is part of any Terms of Sale when using our online store site.  PLEASE KNOW YOU ARE NOT OBLIGATED TO USE OUR WEBSITE OR PURCHASE OUR PRODUCTS, SO BY USING OUR WEBSITES OR BY PURCHASING ANY NEWTEK PRODUCTS IN OUR ONLINE STORE, YOU AGREE TO THESE TERMS, THE WEBSITE TERMS OF USE AND YOU AGREE TO THE USE OF YOUR INFORMATION UNDER THESE TERMS AS WELL AS THE WEBSITE TERMS OF USE, INCORPORATED AS PART OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY.

This Privacy Policy explains how we may gather, track or use information about you through your use of the Website (“Information”). Gathering of Information is only for purpose of improving the Website, products and services provided by NewTek, including customer service, market research or promotional activities (the “Purpose”). NewTek may collect personal data as well as non-personal data. Protecting your data is a top priority for us. The term “personal data” includes any information that enables the identification of a natural person, such as name, physical address, IP address, email address, phone number or behavior. NewTek does not sell personal data to third parties.

**Applicability of this Privacy Policy.**  
This Privacy Policy is applicable to all Information gathered or used by NewTek at the two sites above.

**Use and protection of personal data.**  
We use personal data as part of the Information to process your inquiries or to provide you with access to certain information, or to purchase products on our Website. Granting your permission allows us to process your personal data part of the Information in order to respond more efficiently to your requests, to inform you about new NewTek product offerings or to carry out online communications.

NewTek takes technical and organizational security measures to protect your personal data against unintended deletion, change or loss, as well as to protect against unauthorized transfer or access.

We will respect your wish if you do not want to provide us with your personal data for customer service, market research or promotional purposes. If you no longer wish to receive e-mailings, each e-mail sent contains a link to automatically unsubscribe. If that option doesn’t work for you, you may contact us via telephone, or by sending an email to privacy@newtek.com to request removal from our mailing list.  This may affect your ability to purchase or use the online store however.

**How long will your personal data be stored?**  
How long certain personal data will be stored depends on the nature of the personal data and the purpose for which the personal data will be used. This means that the duration of the storage of your personal data depends per purpose.

**Cookies.**  
“Cookies” are files which store certain information on your computer. When you visit the Website via your computer, it is possible that we will place a cookie on your computer that maintains certain information so that your computer is automatically recognized the next time it visits the Website. Cookies allow us to adapt the Website to your interests, to tailor the information presented to you based on your browsing preferences, such as remembering who you are for product support or personalizing pages and to save your password so that you do not need to re-enter it each visit.

If you do not want us to deploy cookies on your computer, you can set your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when a website tries to put a cookie in your browser software. If you do not reject cookies, we assume that you consent to the use of cookies. Rejecting cookies however may affect your ability to use this Website including the online store.

In the event you request not to be tracked, an anonymous cookie without any personal information will be placed on your computer to prevent another permissions request. If your computer however automatically removes cookies, you will be presented the permission request each time you access the Website. If you chose to share content via Social Sharing buttons, Facebook, Google+, LinkedIn or Twitter you agree to the privacy policies of those individual sites. The actions of social sharing are not covered under the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**Use of Cookies in the Online Store.**  
The following additional terms apply to cookies and private information used on the NewTek online store site, and where in direct conflict with other terms herein, the following terms control with regard to the Online Store:

**What we collect in the Online Store:**  
We may collect the following information:

  * name
  * company name
  * contact information including email address and shipping address
  * demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
  * other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers

For the exhaustive list of cookies we collect in the Online Store see the List of Cookies we collect section below.

**What we do with the information we gather in the Online Store.**  
In addition to other reasons mentioned in this Privacy Policy, we require this information for the Online Store to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * To order and deliver the products you specify
  * Internal record keeping.
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customize the website according to your interests.

**How we use cookies in the Online Store.**  
We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this traffic log information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

**List of cookies we collect in the Online Store.**  
The table below lists the cookies we may collect in the Online Store and what information they store. 

**COOKIE name** | **COOKIE Description**  
---|---  
  
**CART**

| 

The association with your shopping cart.  
  
**CATEGORY_INFO**

| 

Stores the category info on the page, that allows to display pages more quickly.  
  
**COMPARE**

| 

The items that you have in the Compare Products list.  
  
**CURRENCY**

| 

Your preferred currency  
  
**CUSTOMER**

| 

An encrypted version of your customer id with the store.  
  
**CUSTOMER_AUTH**

| 

An indicator if you are currently logged into the store.  
  
**CUSTOMER_INFO**

| 

An encrypted version of the customer group you belong to.  
  
**CUSTOMER_SEGMENT_IDS**

| 

Stores the Customer Segment ID  
  
**EXTERNAL_NO_CACHE**

| 

A flag, which indicates whether caching is disabled or not.  
  
**FRONTEND**

| 

You sesssion ID on the server.  
  
**GUEST-VIEW**

| 

Allows guests to edit their orders.  
  
**LAST_CATEGORY**

| 

The last category you visited.  
  
**LAST_PRODUCT**

| 

The most recent product you have viewed.  
  
**NEWMESSAGE**

| 

Indicates whether a new message has been received.  
  
**NO_CACHE**

| 

Indicates whether it is allowed to use cache.  
  
**PERSISTENT_SHOPPING_CART**

| 

A link to information about your cart and viewing history if you have asked the site.  
  
**POLL**

| 

The ID of any polls you have recently voted in.  
  
**POLLN**

| 

Information on what polls you have voted on.  
  
**RECENTLYCOMPARED**

| 

The items that you have recently compared.  
  
**STF**

| 

Information on products you have emailed to friends.  
  
**STORE**

| 

The store view or language you have selected.  
  
**USER_ALLOWED_SAVE_COOKIE**

| 

Indicates whether a customer allowed to use cookies.  
  
**VIEWED_PRODUCT_IDS**

| 

The products that you have recently viewed.  
  
**WISHLIST**

| 

An encrypted list of products added to your Wishlist.  
  
**WISHLIST_CNT**

| 

The number of items in your Wishlist.  
  
End of Online Store Cookies Section

**Non-Personal Data.**  
In addition to personal data, NewTek may automatically track general Information such as Internet browser and operating system used, domain name of the Website you are coming from, number of visits, average time of use and pages accessed. We use this Information to analyze aggregate traffic patterns throughout this Website to continually improve our online offerings, the Website’s user friendliness, its efficiency, etc. Your identity cannot be determined from this Information and this Information will only be used by NewTek to offer you a product or the service of the Website and to improve it.

**Links to third party sites.**  
This Privacy Policy exclusively addresses the activities of the Website. Other sites (including those that we link to from our Website, and third party sites or services which we co-brand) may have their own policies, which we do not control, and thus are not addressed by this Privacy Policy.

**Product Registration.**  
 Information submitted via our product registration forms is maintained in our registration database, and is used for statistical analysis and internal operations, as well as to update our subscriber lists. When registering your product, only the information that appears with an asterisk is required from you. By providing your email address, you are acknowledging that we may send you periodic product announcements, and other information related to NewTek. You may contact us at 1-800-843-8934 to remove your email information from our database.

**Information Requests.**  
NewTek uses the Web to better educate customers about our products. For this reason, we may have forms on our site that can be used to request specific information. If you request information, you will receive it in the manner described on the form (postal mail, email, telephone contact, etc.). We will use the information you provide, to contact you in the method you prefer.  We may use that information for other purposes including marketing, but we will not sell that information to third parties. By providing your email address to us, you are acknowledging that we may send you periodic product announcements, and other information related to NewTek.

**Event Registration.**  
Sometimes we may provide for registering for events on our website.  When you register for an event, your contact information may be added to our database for future communication, or for statistical purposes.

 **Product Purchases.**  
Information is collected at the time of a sale in order to complete the sale, and deliver the products. Customer lists are not sold or distributed to third parties. Credit/debit card transactions are processed by Authorize.net.  NewTek does not maintain a copy of the credit/debit card or account numbers on its servers, although it may maintain address information if it is part of the Account that you set up with NewTek’s online store.  The purchase price and the credit/debit card information including card number, address and ccv number, is supplied to Authorize.net.  Information collected during transactions may be maintained in their databases for accounting and billing purposes.

**Risks of Hacking**.   
It is important to remember that whatever you transmit or disclose online can be collected and used by others or unlawfully intercepted by third-parties. No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially reasonable means to protect your information, we cannot warrant the security of any information you transmit to us.

**Passwords.**  
Any site account, such as at our online store, may be password protected. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. At no time will any NewTek ask for your password via e-mail. If you ever receive such an inquiry, please notify NewTek immediately at privacy@newtek.com. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your member names, passwords and/or other account information.

**Applicable Law.**     
These Terms of Use and any disputes relating to these Terms of Use or the website will be governed by the laws of the State of Texas, United States of America, without regard to its principles of conflicts of laws. You further agree to accept service of process by certified mail, return receipt requested at the address designated by you. NewTek will be entitled to recover court costs and reasonable attorneys' fees and expenses incurred in successfully proving any claim including any claim for damages or in equity.

**Updates.**  
NewTek may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If so, NewTek will make the revised Privacy Policy available through this Website. We cannot provide you with any separate notice of that fact, so please check back regularly for any updates.
